<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Frontend on teukka.tech</title><link>https://teukka.tech/tags/frontend/</link><description>Recent content in Frontend on teukka.tech</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>taylor@teukka.tech (taylor thompson)</managingEditor><webMaster>taylor@teukka.tech (taylor thompson)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://teukka.tech/tags/frontend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build Your Own Frontend Framework Part 2, Data Fetching</title><link>https://teukka.tech/posts/2019-10-01-byoff-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>taylor@teukka.tech (taylor thompson)</author><guid>https://teukka.tech/posts/2019-10-01-byoff-part-2/</guid><description>Part Two, Data Fetching on Mount Asynchronous actions are essential in any modern web application. The ability to fetch data from some service and display it to users is an important part of building a framework to support these applications. In order for our components to do this, we need to refactor. Our component calls mount when we want to render it on the page, but this function only serves to attach styles and event handlers to the component, not fetch data asynchronously.</description></item><item><title>Build Your Own Frontend Framework, Introduction</title><link>https://teukka.tech/posts/2019-09-09-build-your-own-frontend-framework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>taylor@teukka.tech (taylor thompson)</author><guid>https://teukka.tech/posts/2019-09-09-build-your-own-frontend-framework/</guid><description>Welcome to build your own frontend framework project! I will be coding this live on my twitch stream. Blog posts will come after the streams.
Goals Become more familiar with some of the concepts that power modern frontend frameworks. Gain a deeper understanding of some of the challenges that arise in creating a JavaScript framework. Get better at writing JavaScript. See how different frameworks solve common problems. Non Goals Build a production ready, competitive framework.</description></item></channel></rss>