<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming on teukka.tech</title><link>https://teukka.tech/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in Programming on teukka.tech</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://teukka.tech/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Webtober 2025 Week 4 Roundup - Music Tagger</title><link>https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-28-webtober-week4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-28-webtober-week4/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first year that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to publish something on or for the web for the month of October. Webtober has been a good opportunity to hack on some projects and work on my blog! See what I did last week &lt;a href="https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-14-webtober-week3/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="projects"&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past week and change, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my time working &lt;a href="https://pub.teukka.tech/music/"&gt;music tagger&lt;/a&gt;, an application for adding tags and descriptions to music from streaming services. I&amp;rsquo;ve been frustrated with the lack of organization options present in Spotify. When I create a new playlist for myself or for a friend, I usually have a vibe or theme in my mind. It can be hard to then scour through songs and albums that aren&amp;rsquo;t already in a playlist with a similar theme. Music tagger allows you to paste in the link from Spotify or Tidal and then categorize the song/album as you wish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Webtober 2025 Week 3 Roundup</title><link>https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-22-webtober-week3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-22-webtober-week3/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first year that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to publish something on or for the web for the month of October. Webtober has been a good opportunity to hack on some projects and work on my blog! See what I did last week &lt;a href="https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-14-webtober-week2/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="projects"&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of what I did in the third week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent a lot of time on a project that I will hopefully release at the end of this week!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made the week in review blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project to help me better organize and categorize the music I listen to on Spotify. I&amp;rsquo;ve long felt that playlists are a bad way to organize music since I prefer to listen to whole albums. This project will allow you to add tags and descriptions to songs and albums so that you can easily find music again that fits a certain mood or feeling.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Webtober 2025 Week 2 Roundup</title><link>https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-14-webtober-week2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-14-webtober-week2/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first year that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to publish something on or for the web for the month of October. Webtober has been a good opportunity to hack on some projects and work on my blog! See what I did last week &lt;a href="https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-07-webtober/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="projects"&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of what I did in the second week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made an app for creating energy/aura/vibe spheres: &lt;a href="https://tools.teukka.tech/spheres/"&gt;https://tools.teukka.tech/spheres/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a post showcasing &lt;a href="https://teukka.tech/photos/california-35mm/"&gt;some of my photos&lt;/a&gt; I took in California a year ago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked on integrating ATProto logins to a yet unreleased side project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made the week in review blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did miss a day this week, but that&amp;rsquo;s life! I enjoyed making the spheres app a lot, and might add some more features or do a similar project this week.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Webtober 2025 Week 1 Roundup</title><link>https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-07-webtober/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teukka.tech/posts/2025-10-07-webtober/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first year that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to publish something on or for the web for the month of October. Webtober has been a good opportunity to hack on some projects and work on my blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="projects"&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of what I did in the first week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated my website to include a &lt;a href="https://teukka.tech/feeds"&gt;feeds page&lt;/a&gt; that shows which RSS feeds to which I&amp;rsquo;m subscribed.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will automatically pull updates from my RSS reader server and publish them on my blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a &lt;a href="https://github.com/jamestthompson3/pagenotes"&gt;Firefox Plugin&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to save a bit of highlighted text on a page and navigate to it using &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/URI/Reference/Fragment/Text_fragments"&gt;text fragments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a way to add a note to a saved highlight in the extension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two days of restructuring how photos are presented in my blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing this blog post!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried choose projects that I can get done in an hour or two so that it is easier to get something done.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What's next for Tendril Wiki</title><link>https://teukka.tech/posts/tendril-wiki-future/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teukka.tech/posts/tendril-wiki-future/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="https://teukka.tech/posts/tendril-wiki-lessons/"&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, I discussed some of the lessons I learned from building my personal knowledge management tool, Tendril Wiki. I want to discuss my vision for the tool and ideas around knowledge management. The main goal of Tendril Wiki is to collapse the tools I use for managing information into a single, unified platform. The functionality in Tendril Wiki arises from my own personal needs or from features I&amp;rsquo;ve seen other platforms / tools implement and wanted for myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lessons from Building Tendril Wiki</title><link>https://teukka.tech/posts/tendril-wiki-lessons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teukka.tech/posts/tendril-wiki-lessons/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past year and half, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a knowledge management tool called, &lt;a href="https://github.com/jamestthompson3/tendril-wiki"&gt;Tendril Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve used it to organize my thoughts and catalogue information both at work and in my personal life. Tendril Wiki has served as a place for me to experiment with tooling ideas, gain more experience using the Rust programming language, and copy concepts from other tools for thought. After 18 months, I want to reflect on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned and where I can improve.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://teukka.tech/updates/44844/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 12:27:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teukka.tech/updates/44844/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a crappy version of something is the first step to creating a better version of something. It also helps you know what you don&amp;rsquo;t know :)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://teukka.tech/updates/35750/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:55:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teukka.tech/updates/35750/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The more I use Rust, the more I appreciate how good the built in tooling is. Not having to configure separate test runners, packagers, package managers, etc for each project results in a huge reduction of mental overhead and allows you to just focus on writing code&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://teukka.tech/updates/54883/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 15:14:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teukka.tech/updates/54883/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;humans are quickly overwhelmed by concurrency and find it much more difficult to reason about concurrent than sequential code. Even careful people miss possible inter-leavings among even simple collections of partially ordered operations.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;H. Sutter and J. Larus. Software and the concurrency revolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that source code starts its life as text is part of what makes wrapping my head around concurrent programs difficult. Closure syntax like that in Rust&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;std::thread::spawn&lt;/code&gt; certainly help, but it still gets very tricky to keep things straight. I wonder what a non text interface for concurrent programming would look like&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>