<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>web development on Taylor Thompson's Blog</title><link>https://teukka.tech/tags/web-development/</link><description>Recent content in web development on Taylor Thompson's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>taylor@teukka.tech (taylor thompson)</managingEditor><webMaster>taylor@teukka.tech (taylor thompson)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://teukka.tech/tags/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Javascript Quick Tip -- Browser Notifications</title><link>https://teukka.tech/posts/2020-05-16-notifications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>taylor@teukka.tech (taylor thompson)</author><guid>https://teukka.tech/posts/2020-05-16-notifications/</guid><description>Let &amp;lsquo;Em Know While notifications are one of the browser features that are often abused and lead to obnoxious spam, there are still use cases where notifications enhance the experience of your web application. Modern browsers (with the exception of iOS Safari), support two types of notifications: push, and web. This post discusses only web notifications, since they do not require registration on a server, or the use of a service worker (although they can be used with both).</description></item><item><title>Build Your Own Frontend Framework Part 2, Data Fetching</title><link>https://teukka.tech/posts/2019-10-01-byoff-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>taylor@teukka.tech (taylor thompson)</author><guid>https://teukka.tech/posts/2019-10-01-byoff-part-2/</guid><description>Part Two, Data Fetching on Mount Asynchronous actions are essential in any modern web application. The ability to fetch data from some service and display it to users is an important part of building a framework to support these applications. In order for our components to do this, we need to refactor. Our component calls mount when we want to render it on the page, but this function only serves to attach styles and event handlers to the component, not fetch data asynchronously.</description></item></channel></rss>